# HUONG DO

1 Cobble Court, Farmington, CT 06032 860-997-1998 • huong426@yahoo.com

## **Professional Summary**

An extremely self-motivated, challenge seeking and adaptable team player with almost ten years of experience in mortgage operations. Extensive knowledge of licensing, compliance and human resource. Able to produce quality work in a high pressure and fast paced environments. Proficient in quickly mastering new technology and processes.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# 1st Alliance Lending, LLC • East Hartford, CT • 10/2005 to Present

#### **Executive Vice President**

Oversee operations including licensing, compliance, processing, underwriting, post closing and human resource.

- Responsible for developing and coordinating business planning and policy meetings.
- Ensure compliance procedures are being enforced.
- Maintain and monitor quality control procedures adhering to HUD and State requirements.
- Handle all licensing and investor dealings.
- Oversee accounting audits and banking examinations.
- Coordinated implementation of LOS system.
- Execute complex cross-functional HR strategic initiatives and incorporate processes and policies.
- Created an efficient, productive and team centric work environment allowing employees to grow in their knowledge base.

## Aegis Lending Corporation • East Hartford, CT • 2/2002 to 9/2005

#### **Regional Assistant**

Supported Regional Vice President with business expansion and growth.

- Prepared management reports and maintained proper records of files.
- Responsible for arranging and attending meetings with upper management.
- Planned and coordinated conferences.
- Oversaw training and recruiting of employees.
- Handled licensing and compliance related issues.
- Prepared innovative strategies and plans to achieve the goals of the region.

## Quiznos Sub • Manchester & Hartford, CT • 2/2004 to 9/2009

## Owner

Coordinated opening of 2 franchise locations.

- Responsible for keeping proper records of all business dealings.
- Created marketing strategies to attract business.
- Adhered to franchise customer service procedures and product display rules.
- Prepared sales, expense and payroll reports.
- Worked with accounting firm to prepare financials.
- Conducted and provided proper staffing with qualified personnel.

### Bailey Banks & Biddle • Farmington, CT • 9/2001 to 9/2006

#### **Sales Associate**

Educated consumers on jewelry product while ensuring customer satisfaction.

- Assisted customers in obtaining desired merchandise.
- Key holder Opened and closed store.
- Responsible for receiving and restocking inventory.
- Handled daily register reports and prepared bank deposits.

## Hartford Public Schools – Parkville Elementary • Hartford, CT • 9/2001 to 12/2001

#### 5<sup>th</sup> Grade Teacher

Facilitated student learning and curriculum development.

- Developed and implemented lesson plans and special assignments as a tool to increase alertness and coordination among the students.
- Assessed students' personal growth.
- Participated and carried out various guardian-teacher discussions.
- Taught before and after class programs for CMT preparation.

## Michaels Jewelry • Farmington, CT • 9/1996 to 9/2001

#### Sales Associate

Educated consumers on jewelry product while ensuring customer satisfaction.

- Assisted customers in obtaining desired merchandise.
- Assisted in training sales employees.
- Handled minor watch and jewelry repairs.
- Completed diamond training and earned silver loop.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science Degree in Education -- University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT- 1996 to 2000 Master of Art Degree in Education -- University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT- 2000 to 2001

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

2009-Present: Member of NMLS Industry Development Working Group

2002-2005: Volunteer as Vietnamese Teacher

1999-2001: University of CT, KUBE-Volunteer for big brother big sister program

2001: University of CT, Co-Chair for Asian Gala (Scholarship fundraiser event)

1999: University of CT, Vice President of Vietnamese Student Association

1997: University of CT, President of Asian American Association

1996: University of CT, Treasurer of Asian American Association